<problem display_name="Attempt-Based Partial Credit" showanswer="always" weight="10" attempts="">

<p>The library is capable of awarding reduced credit based on the attempt number for the student. A python function converts the attempt number into a maximum amount of credit. We provide three built-in functions, but you're welcome to write your own.</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>LinearCredit</code>: Linearly decreasing credit to a minimum</li>
  <li><code>GeometricCredit</code>: Maximum credit decreases by a factor for each attempt</li>
  <li><code>ReciprocalCredit</code>: Maximum credit is 1 / attempt number</li>
</ul>

<p>In the below example, we use <code>LinearCredit</code> (but we modify it so that it "resets" every 10 attempts, so attempts 11, 21, 31, ... are treated like attempt 1 for the purpose of this demonstration, as you have no way to reset your attempts!).</p>

<p>For a student's first attempt, they can be awarded maximum credit. A student's second attempt will be awarded at most 80%. Each attempt will decrease the maximum by 20%, to a minimum of 20%. When credit is decreased because of attempt-based partial credit, students receive a message informing them of this by default.</p>

<p>The answer is "cat".</p>

<script type="text/python" system_path="python_lib">
from mitxgraders import *

# This modification wraps the attempt number around at 10
def modified_creditor(attempt):
    newattempt = (attempt - 1) % 10 + 1
    creditor = LinearCredit()
    return creditor(newattempt)

grader = StringGrader(attempt_based_credit=modified_creditor)
</script>

<!-- Note the extra argument to the customresponse tag! -->
<customresponse cfn="grader" expect="cat" cfn_extra_args="attempt">
  <textline />
</customresponse>


<p>Note that attempt-based partial credit applies to all graders; this is just an example of using it with a <code>StringGrader</code>. It's also possible to set course-wide defaults to apply attempt-based partial credit to all your questions through the use of a plugin (which we provide a sample for).</p>


<p><a href="https://github.com/mitodl/mitx-grading-library/tree/master/course/problem/string6.xml" target="_blank">View source</a></p>

</problem>
